Guide to the Maria Mitchell Papers, 1843-2016 (bulk 1853-1889)
Vassar College Libraries Archives and Special Collections
- SERIES IV. MITCHELL NOTES, LECTURE NOTES, AND NOTEBOOKS, 1843-1893
  - Notebooks and Scrapbooks
    - Notebook: [untitled], undated (Folder 12.4)
    - Notebook: [Caroline] E. Furness, M. M, R. L. Kimball, McGlynn Center, undated (Folder 13.1)
    - Notebook: Meteors, undated (Folder 13.2)
    - Notebook/scrapbook on Chauvenet, 1872 (Folder 13.3)
    - Notebook/scrapbook on Chauvenet, undated (Folder 13.4)
    - Notebook: Sun spots, 15 Mar 1883 - 12 June 1893 (Folder 13.5)
    - Notebook: Observations for latitude, undated (Folder 13.6.)
    - Notebook: Memoirs of the Royal Astronomical Society, Vols. XVIII-L, Years 1848-1891, approximately 1891 (Folder 13.7.)
- SERIES V. BIOGRAPHICAL INFORMATION, 1874-2007
  - Biographical notes, undated (Folder 14.1)
  - Association for the Advancement of Woman. Committee on Science circular, [undated] (Folder 14.2)
  - Bust of Maria Mitchell, 1874-1968 (Folder 14.3)
  - Maria Mitchell Endowment Fund, 1887-1897 (Folder 14.4)
  - Death of Maria Mitchell, 1889 (Folder 14.5)
  - Nantucket Maria Mitchell Association, 1902-1926 (Folder 14.6)
  - Nantucket Maria Mitchell Association, 1930-1938, 1968, 2002 [undated] (Folder 14.7)
  - Nantucket Maria Mitchell Association - Poster and fascimilie of map of Nantucket surveyed by Wm. Mitchell, circa 2001-2007 (Map Case — Drawer 37)
  - Hall of Fame, New York University, 1907-1925 (Folder 14.8)
  - Evalyn A. Clark Symposium: Maria Mitchell and Her Influence, 1989 (Folder 14.9)
  - Maria Mitchell-Daughter of Nantucket, 1997 (Folder 14.10)
- SERIES VI. BIOGRAPHIES OF MARIA MITCHELL, 1932, 1984
  - "Maria Mitchell, Pioneer Woman Astronomer" by Dorrit Hoffleit, 1984 (Folder 14.10)
  - "Maria Mitchell and Vassar College - Club Paper" by Mary A. Mineah [?], [1932] (Folder 14.11)
  - "Life and Work" by Mary Whitney, pp. 1-9, undated (Folder 14.12)
  - "Life and Work" by Mary Whitney, pp. 10-22, undated (Folder 14.13)
  - "Life and Work" by Mary Whitney, [another draft], undated (Folder 14.14)
  - [Untitled, by unknown author], undated (Folder 14.15)
- SERIES VII. PUBLICATIONS, 1796-1995
  - Works from the library of Maria Mitchell
    - The Domain of Physiology, by T. Sterry Hunt (Boston: 1882) (Folder 15.1)
    - Instructions for Observing the Transit of Venus, December 6, 1882(Washington: 1882) with photograph of transit of Venus taken at Vassar College,December 1882 (Folder 15.2)
    - The Shorter Catechism of the Westminster Assembly (NY: [n. d.]) (Folder 15.3)
    - "View of Dr. Herschel's Telescope" [engraving] with page from The Universal Magazine, 1796 (Folder 15.4)
  - Works about Maria Mitchell
    - Maria Mitchell bibliography (Folder 15.5)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1858-1896 (Folder 15.6)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1910-1942 (Folder 15.7)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1949-1966 (Folder 15.8)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1968-1995 (Folder 15.9)
    - Newspaper clippings, undated (Folder 15.10)
    - Correspondence Relative to the Award of the King of Denmark's Comet Medal to Miss Maria Mitchell of Nantucket ... (Cambridge: 1857) with Maria Mitchell Library reprint and holograph notebook of the work (Folder 15.11)
  - Journal articles, Book Chapters, and Pamphlets
    - Publications, 1868, 1886-1893 (Folder 16.1)
    - Publications, 1895-1936 (Folder 16.2)
    - Publications, 1938-1968 (Folder 16.3)
    - Publications, 1969-1979 (Folder 16.4)
    - Publications, 1989-1990, undated (Folder 16.5)
- SERIES VIII. OVERSIZED MATERIAL, undated
  - Fingerprints of Maria Mitchell, undated (Folder 17.1)
  - Pencil portrait by C. Wenige of William and Lydia Coleman Mitchell, parents of Maria, [prob. before 1855] (Folder 17.2)
  - Engraving of Maria Mitchell, undated (Folder 17.3)
  - Mitchell family coat of arms, undated (Folder 17.4)
  - Plan of Sherburne Bluffs, Nantucket, Mass, undated (Folder 17.5)
- SERIES IX. MICROFILM, 1831-1888
  - William Mitchell. Autobiography. b. 20 December 1791 (Reel 1, Item 1)
  - William & Maria Mitchell Correspondence [with scientists such as]: (Reel 1, Item 2)
  - G. B. Airy (Reel 1, Item 2)
  - A. D. Bache (Reel 1, Item 2)
  - J. F. Bowditch (Reel 1, Item 2)
  - Alvan Clark (Reel 1, Item 2)
  - James D. Dana (Reel 1, Item 2)
  - C. H. Davis (Reel 1, Item 2)
  - B. A. Gould (Reel 1, Item 2)
  - Edward Everett Hale (Reel 1, Item 2)
  - Joseph G. Harlan (Reel 1, Item 2)
  - Joseph Henry (Reel 1, Item 2)
  - Mathew Fontain Maury (Reel 1, Item 2)
  - Benjamin Pierce (Reel 1, Item 2)
  - and others (Reel 1, Item 2)
  - William Mitchell Observations of the Eclipse of the Sun. 1831 (Reel 1, Item 3)
  - William Mitchell Meterological Observations at Nantucket, 1857-1861 (Reel 1, Item 4)
  - at Lynn, Mass, 1861-1865 (Reel 1, Item 4)
  - William Mitchell Meterological Observations continued by Maria Mitchell, 1865 1869-1872 (Reel 1, Item 5)
  - William Mitchell Meterological Observations at Nantucket, July 1849-1856 (Reel 1, Item 6)
  - William Mitchell Observations made for the purpose of correcting the chronometers of whale ships. Also includes observations of the Comet of 1847 for which Maria Mitchell obtained the gold medal from the King of Denmark, 1845-1850 (Reel 2, Item 7)
  - William Mitchell Manuscript of a lecture on comets, 1842 (Reel 2, Item 8)
  - William Mitchell Correspondence with family and personal friends. (Reel 2, Item 9)
  - William Mitchell Lecture on stars (Reel 2, Item 10)
  - William Mitchell (Reel 2, Item 11)
  - Notebook, astronomical records, surveying notes. Account of Encke's Comet by Walter Folger. (Reel 2, Item 11)
  - William Mitchell Lectures on the moon, distances, eclipses. (Reel 2, Item 12)
  - William Mitchell Meterological Observations, 1844-1849 (Reel 2, Item 13)
  - William Mitchell Journal of Weather [Nantucket], 1848 (Reel 2, Item 14)
  - Scrapbook and clippings, 1835-1840 (Reel 2, Item 14)
  - William Mitchell A brief memoir of the late Walter Folger (Reel 2, Item 15)
  - Maria Mitchell Diary On travels in Europe[George Airy] Poems for children, 1854-1857 (Reel 2, Item 16)
  - Maria Mitchell Lectures telling of trip to Europe and Russia Travels with the Hawthornes, 1873 (Reel 2, Item 17)
  - Stay in Rome Visit to Vatican Observatory and Angelo Secci Lectures to students on Women's Rights, 1857-1858 (Reel 2, Item 17)
  - Maria Mitchell Correspondence relating to the awarding of the gold medal [William Mitchell, letters from Edward Everett, 1848-1864] (Reel 3, Item 18)
  - Maria Mitchell Lecture notes: observations to be made by students (Reel 3, Item 19)
  - Maria Mitchell Lecture notes: lessons in observing [1866] [class notes: 1866] (Reel 3, Item 20)
  - Maria Mitchell Notes on Saturn 1877-1883 Diary notes 1882 (Reel 3, Item 21)
  - Maria Mitchell Lecture notes: notes on meteors and some correspondence (Reel 3, Item 22)
  - Maria Mitchell Lecture notes: notes on distances., 1870 (Reel 3, Item 23)
  - Maria Mitchell Lecture notes: combination of ideas for lectures and diary, 1880-1881 (Reel 3, Item 24)
  - Maria Mitchell Questions for students - test, etc. (Reel 3, Item 25)
  - Maria Mitchell Notes to Chauvenet - eclipses (Reel 3, Item 26)
  - Maria Mitchell Lectures on precession, sun spots, constellations, occultations, cycles of time, comets. Some diary notes for 1867 and [class notes 1867] (Reel 3, Item 27)
  - Maria Mitchell[Introductory lecture - remarks on distance of stars] [class notes] (Reel 3, Item 28)
  - Maria Mitchell Lecture: Ideas on Observing, on Women, [1874] (Reel 3, Item 29)
  - Diary notes, 1872 and 1873 (Reel 3, Item 29)
  - Maria Mitchell Subjects of lectures given by students at Vassar and subjects of lectures given by Maria Mitchell, 1881-1887 (Reel 4, Item 30)
  - Maria Mitchell Notes and printed references on nautical Almanac. Studies in preparation for computational work done for U.S. Nautical Almanac first published in 1849. (Reel 4, Item 31)
  - Maria Mitchell Lecture notes, undated (Reel 4, Item 32)
  - Observations of Saturn and its satellites, 1879-1882 and 1877- (Reel 4, Item 32)
  - Observations on Mars, 1869 (Reel 4, Item 32)
  - Lecture notes on the possibility of an intermercurial planet read in Nov 1869 (Reel 4, Item 32)
  - Observations on Mira, 1856-1858 (Reel 4, Item 32)
  - Lectures on Seasons (Reel 4, Item 32)
  - Lectures on double stars (Reel 4, Item 32)
  - Lectures on early astronomers (Reel 4, Item 32)
  - Maria Mitchell Lectures on the Eclipse of 7 August 1869. (Reel 4, Item 33)
  - Lectures on the Sun and Moon. (Reel 4, Item 33)
  - Lectures on Saturn. (Reel 4, Item 33)
  - Lectures on the Importance of Using Your Eyes. (Reel 4, Item 33)
  - Lectures on the Size of the Universe (Reel 4, Item 33)
  - Lectures on the Moon [with photograph] and the Moon's Phases. (Reel 4, Item 33)
  - Motion of the Planets and their Discovery. (Reel 4, Item 33)
  - Lecture on La Place read February 1868. (Reel 4, Item 33)
  - Lectures on Accidents in Observing (Reel 4, Item 33)
  - Observations of Comets made in Nantucket. (Reel 4, Item 33)
  - Observations of Comets made at Vassar, 1881-1882 (Reel 4, Item 33)
  - Lecture on Alvan Clark and Telescope Making. (Reel 4, Item 33)
  - Notes on Gauss [Nantucket} (Reel 4, Item 33)
  - William and Maria Mitchell (Reel 4, Item 34)
  - Letters of William, Henry and Maria Mitchell (Reel 4, Item 34)
  - Poems written by Maria Mitchell. (Reel 4, Item 34)
  - Accounts of activities at Vassar [copied from the College newspaper]. (Reel 4, Item 34)
  - Obituary notices and miscellaneous memorials to Maria Mitchell. (Reel 4, Item 34)
  - Book of clippings on astronomical observations made by other astronomers. (Reel 5, Item 35)
  - Correspondence with Sir George Airy and Lady Airy, 1857-1882 (Reel 5, Item 36)
  - Diary notes and Ideas on Women's Education, 1886-1888. Including some observations, 1887-1888. (Reel 5, Item 37)
  - William and Maria Mitchell (Reel 5, Item 38)
  - Autographs, miscellaneous. (Reel 5, Item 38)
  - Letters to William Mitchell from well-known people, 1825 (Reel 5, Item 38)
  - Letters to and from Maria Mitchell (Reel 5, Item 38)
  - Clippings on Astronomers, on Vassar (Reel 5, Item 39)
  - Reports of Comet observations; additional clippings on science and women, etc. (Reel 5, Item 39)
  - Maria Mitchell Letters to Maria Mitchell and clippings on astronomical subjects, [1881-1888(?)] (Reel 5, Item 40)
  - William Mitchell Clippings on women and astronomy, obituary of William Mitchell, computations. (Reel 5, Item 41)
  - Maria Mitchell Early letters to Maria Mitchell received during her trip to Europe, 1857-1858 (Reel 5, Item 42)
  - Maria Mitchell Photograph and calling cards [Scrapbook of views & calling cards of European trip, 1857-1858(?)] (Reel 6, Item 43)
  - William and Maria Mitchell Letters to Maria Mitchell from astronomers (1869) after her father's death. (Reel 6, Item 44)
  - Obituaries of William Mitchell (Reel 6, Item 44)
  - Maria Mitchell Lecture notes and diary, 1881-1882 (Reel 6, Item 45)
  - [Maria Mitchell private notes 1881-1882] (Reel 6, Item 45)
  - Maria Mitchell Notebook on the Women's Congress [Association for the Advancement of Women 1880-1881] (Reel 6, Item 46)
  - Maria Mitchell Notebook on the Women's Congress 1876. Questionnaire and Statistics on Women in Science. (Reel 6, Item 47)
  - Maria Mitchell Private notes and journal, 1873, includes clippings. (Reel 6, Item 48)
  - Accounts of travel to Europe. (Reel 6, Item 48)
  - Maria Mitchell European notes, 1873 (Reel 6, Item 49)
  - Maria Mitchell Ideas on science and its popularization, 1874 (Reel 6, Item 50)
  - [Commonplace book, 1871-1880] (Reel 6, Item 50)
  - On government and patronage (Reel 6, Item 50)
  - On English gentlemen (Reel 6, Item 50)
  - On music (Reel 6, Item 50)
  - On transit of Venus, 1874 (Reel 6, Item 50)
  - On Women's Congress, 1875-1876 (Reel 6, Item 50)
  - Life in the college, 1875 (Reel 6, Item 50)
  - Visit of Don Pedro, 1876 (Reel 6, Item 50)
  - Diary, 1878, 1879, 1880 (Reel 6, Item 50)
  - Maria Mitchell Clippings on Women's Congress in an old computations book, 1865 (Reel 6, Item 51)
  - Genealogy of the Mitchell Family, Phebe Mitchell [1864] [Chase, Joseph, A book of genealogy, 1815, copied by Phebe Mitchell, 1844] (Reel 6, Item 52)
  - List of Shares sold for social library (Reel 6, Item 52)
  - "Scraps to be saved about Jupiter," etc. (Reel 6, Item 53)
  - Lectures on Saturn, Jupiter, Color of Stars, Women's Labor (Reel 6, Item 54)
  - Book of clippings, engravings (Reel 6, Item 55)
  - Obituaries of Edward Everett (Reel 6, Item 55)
  - Maria Mitchell at Vassar (Reel 6, Item 55)
  - Accounts of Life at Vassar (Reel 6, Item 55)
  - Obituaries and Accounts of the activities of William and Maria Mitchell (Reel 6, Item 55)
  - Letters from Maria Mitchell's students and famous people like John G. Whittier, John D. Rockefeller. (Reel 7, Item 56)
  - [Letters to Maria Mitchell, 1886] (Reel 7, Item 56)
  - "Scraps from newspapers, not very important." (Reel 7, Item 57)
  - Reminiscences of the Herschels (Reel 7, Item 58)
  - Lectures by Maria Mitchell (Reel 7, Item 58)
  - "Letters and Scraps -- some of them are very valuable." (Reel 7, Item 59)
  - Letters of Introduction from George Bond to famous European astronomers, 1865 (Reel 7, Item 59)
  - Letters of famous astronomers to Maria Mitchell. (Reel 7, Item 59)
  - Letters from famous women, such as Dorothea Dix, Julia Ward Howe, Frances Willard - to Maria Mitchell (Reel 7, Item 59)
  - Maria Mitchell Printed Papers, articles in magazines and newspapers by Maria Mitchell (Reel 7, Item 60)
  - Maria Mitchell Diary of trip to Europe 1857-1858 (Copy Book Copy) (Reel 7, Item 61)
  - Maria Mitchell Diary account of a western trip, 1857, includes voyages on the Mississippi and travels through the south. Copied by William Mitchell. (Reel 7, Item 62)
  - Lectures on Jupiter; on scientists and the popularization of science, on time [parts very faint]. (Reel 7, Item 63)
  - William Mitchell Kendall Autobiography and journal (European trip, 1881) (Reel 7, Item 65)
  - Phebe Mitchell Kendall Diaries. (Reel 8, Item 66)
  - Maria Mitchell Lecture on the moon (Reel 8, Item 67)
  - Scrapbook containing letters to Maria Mitchell, 1870-1875 (Reel 8, Item 68)
  - Maria Mitchell Astronomical story. (Reel 8, Item 69)
  - William Mitchell Lecture on meteorology (Reel 8, Item 69a)
  - Report on a visitation to the Harvard Observatory (Reel 8, Item 69a)
  - Maria Mitchell Letters [1 volume] (Reel 8, Item 69b)
  - Maria Mitchell [actually Phebe Kendall] Diary in Europe, Part I [Part II is actually in Reel 8, item 66.] (Reel 9, Item 69c)
  - Maria Mitchell Travel notes [1 volume] (Reel 9)
  - Nantucket Athenaeum Library, Item 1 - Maria Mitchell, Weather Observations, 1846-1849, 1854-1856 (Reel 9)
  - Nantucket Athenaeum Library, Item 2 - Maria Mitchell, Weather Observations, 1850-1853 (Reel 9)
  - Nantucket Athenaeum Library, Item 3 - Maria Mitchell, Weather Observations, 1854-1856 (Reel 9)
  - Nantucket Athenaeum Library, Item 4 - Letter from Robley Dunglison to Nantucket Athenaeum, 1846 (Reel 9)
  - Nantucket Athenaeum Library, Item 5 - Letter from Maria Mitchell to officers of Nantucket Athenaeum, no year (Reel 9)
- SERIES X. GLASS PLATE NEGATIVES, 1871-1890
  - Prints of select negatives used in the Vassar College Library exhibition "Seeing the Sun: Maria Mitchell’s Observations, 1868-1888," matted, 2016 (Boxes 18-19)
  - Observed by Mitchell and Braislin, 1871 Nov 25 (Neg. Box 1)
  - Observed by Mitchell and Lupton, 1872 Apr 19 (Neg. Box 31)
  - Observed by Foster and Lupton, 1872 Apr 27 (Neg. Box 31)
    Notes: "Duplicate."
  - Observed by Lupton and Foster, 1872 Apr 27 (Neg. Box 31)
  - Observed by [unknown], 1872 May 3 (Neg. Box 31)
  - Observed by [unknown], 1872 May 7 (Neg. Box 31)
  - Observed by [unknown], 1872 May 8 (Neg. Box 31)
  - Observed by [unknown], 1872 May 10 (Neg. Box 31)
  - Observed by [unknown], 1872 May 21 (Neg. Box 31)
  - Observed by [unknown], 1872 Jun 6 (Neg. Box 31)
  - Sunspots, observed by "Mr. Mic" (Maria Mitchell), 1872 Oct 21 (Neg. Box 31)
    Notes: "Tolerable "
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton, 1872 Nov 1 (Neg. Box 31)
    Notes: "Pretty good. Three spots visible"
  - Sunspots, observed by [unknown], 1872 Nov 2 (Neg. Box 31)
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Perry, 1872 Nov 7 (Neg. Box 29)
    Notes: "Tolerable. Negative injured. A great number of spots. Thirty at least. Prints from this were taken"
  - Sunspots, observed by Mitchell and Perry, 1872 Nov 9; [envelope only] (Neg. Box 3)
    Notes: "Sun. A string of small spots"
  - Sunspots, observed by Mitchell and Perry, 1872 Nov 9 (Neg. Box 29)
    Notes: "Many spots. A curious triple spot. Duplicate."
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Perry, 1872 Nov 15 (Neg. Box 29)
    Notes: "Tolerable. Large spot on one side."
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Perry, 1872 Nov 21 (Neg. Box 29)
    Notes: "Good. Outline a little marred. Many spots"
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Perry, 1872 Nov 21 (Neg. Box 29)
    Notes: "Good. A line of spots across the sun. Duplicate of this copy was used in making prints"
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Perry, 1872 Nov 27 (Neg. Box 29)
    Notes: "Poor impression. Three groups of spots."
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Perry, 1872 Nov 27 (Neg. Box 29)
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Noble, 1872 Dec 7 (Neg. Box 29)
    Notes: "Tolerable. Several large spots with clearly defined penumbra. One double spot."
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Perry, 1872 Dec 10 (Neg. Box 29)
    Notes: "Poor impression. Three large spots. Two of these [illegible]."
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Perry, 1873 Jan 9 (Neg. Box 28)
    Notes: "Poor. Chemicals not good."
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Perry, 1873 Jan 14 (Neg. Box 3)
    Notes: "Good. 2 large spots (one double) coming on, a small one well towards the center and some small spots going off."
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Perry, 1873 Feb 13 11:55 AM (Neg. Box 28)
    Notes: "Tolerable. 1 large group of spots near center and a large spot separate."
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Perry, 1873 Feb 14 (Neg. Box 31)
    Notes: "Impression too faint. Large group of spots"
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Perry, 1873 Feb 20 (Neg. Box 31)
    Notes: "Tolerable. Many spots scattered over the surface"
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Perry, 1873 Feb 22 12:48 PM (Neg. Box 31)
    Notes: "Tolerable. Spots scattered very much over surface."
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Perry, 1873 Feb 25 (Neg. Box 31)
    Notes: "Tolerable. Group of spots coming on. Two small ones in center and some going off."
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Perry, 1873 Feb 26 12:35 PM (Neg. Box 31)
    Notes: "Poor impression. Group of spots coming on."
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Perry, 1873 Mar 12 (Neg. Box 28)
    Notes: "Pretty good. Duplicate."
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Perry, 1873 Mar 13 (Neg. Box 28)
    Notes: "Good. Negative afterward infused. Large group of spots"
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Perry, 1873 Mar 14 (Neg. Box 28)
    Notes: "Poor. Shaken. Large group."
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Perry, 1873 Mar 17 (Neg. Box 28)
    Notes: "Plate scratched."
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Perry, 1873 Mar 19 12:31 PM (Neg. Box 28)
    Notes: "Too Dark. Angle 9º"
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Perry, 1873 Mar 27 11:51 AM (Neg. Box 31)
    Notes: "Pretty good. Many spots. Scattered."
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Perry, 1873 Apr 1 (Neg. Box 31)
    Notes: "Pretty good "
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Arnold, 1873 Apr 23 (Neg. Box 31)
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Perry, 1873 Apr 29 (Neg. Box 28)
    Notes: "6. Many spots"
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1873 Apr 30 (Neg. Box 34)
    Notes: "Same groups. Picture well defined but incomplete – taken on wrong side of plate"
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Perry, 1873 May 1 11:05 AM (Neg. Box 28)
    Notes: "5. One spot is surrounded by a semi-circle of smaller spots."
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Perry, 1873 May 5 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 31)
    Notes: "4. Few spots"
  - Sunspots, observed by Perry and Arnold, 1873 May 29 (Neg. Box 31)
    Notes: "4"
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Arnold, 1873 Jun 18 (Neg. Box 28)
    Notes: "One small spot coming on."
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Arnold, 1873 Jun 19 (Neg. Box 31)
    Notes: "No additional spots, very small in center"
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Stow, 1873 Jun 20 (Neg. Box 28)
    Notes: "4. Large spots coming on"
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Marsh, 1873 Jun 21 (Neg. Box 28)
    Notes: "4. Duplicate poor."
  - Sunspots, observed by Lupton and Marsh, 1873 Jun 21 (Neg. Box 28)
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1873 Oct (Neg. Box 29)
    Notes: "3. Very few spots"
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1873 Oct 2 12:06 PM (Neg. Box 3)
    Notes: "5. Focus poor; spots few."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1873 Oct 10 12:07 PM (Neg. Box 3)
    Notes: "4. Spots few."
  - Sunspots, observed by Stow and Arnold, 1873 Oct 15 11:45 AM (Neg. Box 29)
    Notes: "1. Spots few."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1873 Oct 16 12:01 PM (Neg. Box 29)
    Notes: "5. Spots small. Few, circular."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1873 Oct 17 11:02 AM (Neg. Box 29)
    Notes: "5. Spots few; faculae surrounding."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1873 Oct 22 12:12 PM (Neg. Box 29)
    Notes: "2. Spots few; faculae coming on and going off."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1873 Oct 23 (Neg. Box 29)
    Notes: "3. Plate scratched; spots few."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1873 Oct 25 12:25 PM (Neg. Box 29)
    Notes: "4. Suspicious spot at top of plate which, as marked, reverses the sun. Two other pictures were taken on this day which are preserved on account of said spot. Spots few. "
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1873 Oct 25 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 29)
    Notes: "3. Duplicate. Preserved on account of small spot on top of the disc, (really in southern part of sun). Spots few."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1873 Oct 25 1:02 PM (Neg. Box 29)
    Notes: "3. Poor focus. This is the 3d. Picture of this date. It was taken on account of a suspicious spot which appeared in the other two. Spots few."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1873 Oct 29 12:12 PM (Neg. Box 29)
    Notes: "4. Spots small, few, circular; faculae"
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1873 Nov 5 12:26 PM (Neg. Box 3)
    Notes: "6°. 7. Spots small faculae."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1873 Nov 6 12:00 PM (Neg. Box 3)
    Notes: "3. Spots few; faculae."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1873 Nov 10 12:17 PM (Neg. Box 36.27)
    Notes: "6º. Many small spots, faculae."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1873 Nov 11 12:08 PM (Neg. Box 25)
    Notes: "Angle of daily motion, 6º. Several spots to right of center. One single spot and one pair to left. "
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1873 Nov 14 11:55 AM (Neg. Box 25)
    Notes: "Angle of Motion 2º. Several small spots, faculae."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1873 Nov 22 12:16 PM (Neg. Box 29)
    Notes: "8. Spots few; faculae."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1873 Nov 25 [12:05 PM?] (Neg. Box 29)
    Notes: "8. Spots few; faint faculae."
  - Sunspots, observed by Stow and Arnold, 1873 Nov 26 12:20 PM (Neg. Box 29)
    Notes: "Two small spots on west limb, one large one just within the east limb."
  - Sunspots, observed by Stow and Arnold, 1873 Nov 29 12:14 PM (Neg. Box 29)
    Notes: "Same spots of Nov. 26, also large spot on east limb. Faculae."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1873 Dec 6; [2 plates] (Neg. Box 3)
    Notes: "Spots good, two single ones. Group near center."